A Guide to the Richmond YWCA Archives 1893-1980
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
- General Files
  - Virginia Council on State Legislation 1967-1970 (Box-folder 33)
  - Virginia Staff Conference (Box-folder 34)
  - VISTA (Box-folder 34)
  - Volunteer Service Bureau (Box-folder 34)
  - Volunteer Time Cards (Box-folder 34)
  - Weekend Conference 1952 (Box-folder 34)
  - Weekend Conference 1953 (Box-folder 34)
  - Welfare Bulletins 1953 (Box-folder 34)
  - What is the YWCA? (Box-folder 34)
  - White House Conference 1970 (Box-folder 34)
  - Who What Y Bulletins (Box-folder 34)
  - Who's Who-YWCA (Box-folder 34)
  - Women and Employment in the South (Box-folder 34)
  - Women and Prison Influence (Box-folder 34)
  - Women's Employment Information Service (Box-folder 34)
  - Women's Rights Project-American Civil Liberties Union Foundation 1978 (Box-folder 34)
  - Women's Rights Propaganda 1976 (Box-folder 34)
  - Women's Rights Report 1979 (Box-folder 34)
  - Work Schedule (Fall) 1952 (Box-folder 34)
  - World Citizenship (Box-folder 34)
  - Worship 1952 (Box-folder 34)
  - Young Adult Publicity 1952 (Box-folder 34)
  - Young Adult Publicity 1968 (Box-folder 34)
  - Young Adults 1968 (Box-folder 34)
  - Young Employed Conference Conference-Rockford College 1953 (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Advisor Training (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Clubs (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Conferences 1954 (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Information (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Information (general) 1968 (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Leadership Training 1967 (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Publicity 1959-1960 (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Recognition Sunday 1965 (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Scholarships and Membership Fees 1952 (Box-folder 34)
  - Y-Teen Summer Job Suggestions 1968 (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA Board Business 1954 (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA Brochures (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA Committee Minutes 1962-1963 (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA Committee Minutes 1963 (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA Committee Minutes 1964 (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA Letterhead (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA Newsletter (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA Staff-Clusters (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA Winston-Slem, NC 1954 (Box-folder 34)
  - YWCA-Young Adult Handbook 1950 (Box-folder 34)
- City Study
  - Know Your City Study (Box-folder 35)
  - Blank Sample Forms (Box-folder 35)
  - Index to Numbered Files (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 1-Colonial and Revolutionary Points of Interest (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 2-Bank (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 3-Transportation Depots and Wharves (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 4-Narrative of Richmond (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 5-Educational Facilities (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 6-Religious Facilities (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 7 and 8-Parks and Photographs (Box-folder 35)
  - Streets and Roads (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 10-Residence of Distinguished Citizens (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 11-James and Kanawha Canal (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 12-Class Minutes (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 13-Conferderate and Reconstruction Points of Interest (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 14-Women Employed in the City (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 15-Diseases (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 16-Health Department (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 17-Mosquitos, Flies, Defects, Blindness (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 18-Blank (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 19-Temperance and Liquor Laws (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 20-Announcements (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 21-Children, Colored, Crime (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 22-Negro Work (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 23-Fire Department (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 24-Libraries (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 25-Women and Labor (Box-folder 35)
  - Number File 26-City Finance and Organization (Box-folder 35)
- Photographs
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box-folder 36)
  - New Clippings Sheets Contatiner (Box-folder 38)
    News Clippings Sheets found inserted in Phyliss Wheatley Y.W.C.A. Brandi album. Clippings related to YWCA and women involved in the workforce in the Spring of 1941
- Scrapbooks
  This section of Richmond Y.W.C.A. scrapbooks is housed in the scrapbook area and has been numbered separately
  - Scrapbook 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1)
  - Scrapbook 1950-1971 (Box-folder 2)
  - Scrapbook 1917-1924 (Box-folder 3)
  - Scrapbook 1925-1931 (Box-folder 4)
  - Scrapbook 1911 (Box-folder 5)
  - Scrapbook 1961-1962 (Box-folder 6)
  - Scrapbook 1930-1974 (Box-folder 7)
  - Scrapbook 1966-1970's (Box-folder 8)
  - Scrapbook 1911-1917 (Box-folder 9)
  - Scrapbook 1953-1956 (Box-folder 10)
  - Scrapbook 1922-1925 (Box-folder 11)
  - Publicity Scrapbook 1944 (Box-folder 12)
  - Scrapbook 1950-1952 (Box-folder 13)
  - Scapbook 1909-1913 (Box-folder 14)
  - Richmond Girl Reserves 1928-1929, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 15)
  - Scrapbook 1983-1984 (Box-folder 16)
  - Richmond Business Girls League 1936 (Box-folder 17)
  - Scrapbook 1931-1937 (Box-folder 18)
  - Scrapbook 1941-1943 (Box-folder 19)
  - Scrapbook 1912-1913 (Box-folder 20)
  - Scrapbook 1914-1918 (Box-folder 21)
  - Scrapbook 1946-1962 (Box-folder 22)
  - Scrapbook 1943 (Box-folder 23)
  - Scrapbook 1945 (Box-folder 24)
  - Scrapbook 1943 (Box-folder 25)
  - Scrapbook 1962 (Box-folder 26)
  - Scrapbook 1957-1959 (Box-folder 27)
  - Scrapbook 1926-1943 (Box-folder 28)
  - Scrapbook, Loose Clippings 1935-1945 (Box-folder 29)
  - Y.W.C.A. Time Book, Scrapbooks 1930-2, 1922-3, 1927-30 (Box-folder 30)
  - Photo Album 1950s-1960s (Box-folder 31)
  - Scrapbook 1946-1951 (Box-folder 32)
  - Richmond Journals 1949, 1952 (Box-folder 33)
  - Loose Clippings 1955-1973 (Box-folder 34)
  - Account Book 1925 (Box-folder 35)
  - Day Camp Book, Account Books, Looseclippings 1940-2, 1930-40 (Box-folder 36)
  - Account Book, Miscellaneous Photographs, Scrapbook 1939-1940, 1940s, 1947 (Box-folder 37)
  - Interracial Committee Scrapbooks 1941-1949, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 38)
  - Phyllis Wheatley Branch Scrapbook 1952-1953 (Box-folder 39)
  - Y.W.C.A. Program Evaluation Posters, Girls Reserves Scrapbook, Miscellaneous Folders 1923-1927 (Box-folder 40)
  - Scrapbook 1941 (Box-folder 41)
  - Phyllis Wheatley Branch Scrapbook 1937-1939 (Box-folder 42)
  - Scrapbooks 1933-1937 (Box-folder 43)
  - Scrapbook 1940s (Box-folder 44)
  - Loose clippings, Scrapbook 1947-1950 (Box-folder 45)
  - Phyllis Wheatley Branch Scrapbook, Loose Clippings (2) 1948-1956 (Box-folder 46)
  - Photoalbum (2), Scrapbook 1952, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 47)
  - Scrapbooks, Loose Clippings 1930-1942 (Box-folder 48)
  - Scrapbooks 1939-1941 (Box-folder 49)
  - Account Book, Phyllis Wheatley Branch Y.W.C.A. Day Camp 1943-1944 (Box-folder 50)
  - Scrapbook, Looseclippings, Spiral Bound Scrapbook 1936 (Box-folder 51)
  - Scrapbooks 1951-1952 (Box-folder 52)
  - Scrapbook Publicity 1950-1957 (Box-folder 53)